<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://status.x4b.net/"/>
    <title>WEB on X4B Network Status</title>
    <link>https://status.x4b.net/affected/web/</link>
    <description>Incident history</description>
    <generator>github.com/cstate</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>2025-11-12T05:07:17+00:00</lastBuildDate>
    <updated>2025-11-12T05:07:17+00:00</updated>
    
    
    
      <atom:link href="https://status.x4b.net/affected/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] HTTP Log information</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-11-12-http-log-information/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-11-12-http-log-information/</guid>
        <category>2025-11-12T05:42:03.702Z</category>
        <description>Update system is fixed. Appears to be a bug in the version of vector deployed at the edge. We have resolved the situation for now and will look into a software update and/or fix tomorrow.
We are investigating an information collecting HTTP information (requests, error logs).</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; system is fixed. Appears to be a bug in the version of vector deployed at the edge. We have resolved the situation for now and will look into a software update and/or fix tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are investigating an information collecting HTTP information (requests, error logs).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Recaptcha Depreciation</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-08-12-recaptcha-depreciation/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 04:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-08-12-recaptcha-depreciation/</guid>
        <category>2025-08-12T04:29:29.120Z</category>
        <description>We are depreciating Recaptcha &amp;amp; recaptcha fallback for validation pages. Currently recaptcha is in use for less than 0.01% of all verification page requests so far in 2025 and with the exception of an attack utilizing a captcha solver (a growing risk that will be mitigated by removal) was similarly represented in 2024.
If any customer requires a no-javascript verification page they may contact us and we will see what we can do, however its our current belief given the analytics gathered from user agents and usage of the default PoW verification system that this is below a significant number.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are depreciating Recaptcha &amp;amp; recaptcha fallback for validation pages. Currently recaptcha is in use for less than 0.01% of all verification page requests so far in 2025 and with the exception of an attack utilizing a captcha solver (a growing risk that will be mitigated by removal) was similarly represented in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any customer requires a no-javascript verification page they may contact us and we will see what we can do, however its our current belief given the analytics gathered from user agents and usage of the default PoW verification system that this is below a significant number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will of course be adding an appropriate message for clients without javascipt enabled when Recaptcha fallback &amp;amp; support is removed before the end of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Cloud Service outage</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-07-27-cloud-service-outage/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 11:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-07-27-cloud-service-outage/</guid>
        <category>2025-07-29T04:51:41.609Z</category>
        <description>Update No update from Akamai yet but we are seeing Kubernetes nodes that were offline return to function slowly starting around 5 minutes ago.
Update We currently await Akamai to fix their internal networking. 4/12 of our cluster nodes are currently online. The panel is up but slow. Some non essential services that rely on inter-node communication are degraded.
Update Panel is currently very slow due to 70% of cloud nodes being offline currently.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; No update from Akamai yet but we are seeing Kubernetes nodes that were offline return to function slowly starting around 5 minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; We currently await Akamai to fix their internal networking. 4/12 of our cluster nodes are currently online. The panel is up but slow. Some non essential services that rely on inter-node communication are degraded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; Panel is currently very slow due to 70% of cloud nodes being offline currently. We await Akamai&amp;rsquo;s resolution to their datacenter outage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We apologise for the inconvenience and are doing everything we can to return to 100%. Even including moving our services to another vendor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.linode.com/incidents/6yw88b0ft94g&#34;&gt;upstream issue&lt;/a&gt; you may.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; We will be keeping this incident open for now as we are still seeing substantially lowered performance in the region and half of our cluster nodes are still unavailable. The panel is however online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continue to monitor the &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.linode.com/incidents/6yw88b0ft94g&#34;&gt;upstream issue&lt;/a&gt; and await resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; We will be keeping this incident open for now as we are still seeing substantially lowered performance in the region and some of our cluster nodes are still unavailable. The panel is however online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; Holy Smokes Akamai that was a long one. Services are restored. We are going through and checking everything in line with our DRP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream Update -
Our SMEs continue to work bringing our services back online, and we will provide an update as progress is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream Update -
Identified - Our team has identified the issue affecting connectivity in our US-EAST (Newark) data center. The issue is related to heating/cooling complications in the data center due to a power outage . The power outage has been fixed and we are working quickly to bring our services back online, and we will provide an update as soon as the solution is in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream currently has an outage affecting their US-EAST PoP where our core cloud (web panel, data collection, etc) is homed. This does not affect customer services are all essential services (BGP, route validation, mitigation analysis) is multi-homed. Email delivery (i.e on DDoS attack) will not be available until service restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Investigating - Our team is investigating an emerging service issue affecting All Services in US-EAST (Newark). We will share additional updates as we have more information.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Autossl issues </title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-07-11-autossl-issues/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 09:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-07-11-autossl-issues/</guid>
        <category>2025-07-13T00:56:26.667Z</category>
        <description>Update - Looks resolved. We will continue to monitor.
Investigating - Issue seems to have been limited to 13/37k certificates we generate. We beleive this was caused by an increase in errors due to a large number of bad certificate generations being attempted.
We have made some changes and are monitoring. Please let us know if you have any issues.
Investigating - We are investigating a potential issue that might affect the uptime of one our of services.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; - Looks resolved. We will continue to monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigating&lt;/em&gt; - Issue seems to have been limited to 13/37k certificates we generate. We beleive this was caused by an increase in errors due to a large number of bad certificate generations being attempted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have made some changes and are monitoring. Please let us know if you have any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigating&lt;/em&gt; - We are investigating a potential issue that might affect the uptime of one our of services. We are sorry for any inconvenience this may cause you. This incident post will be updated once we have more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Issues with Akamai</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-03-30-issues-with-linode/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 11:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2025-03-30-issues-with-linode/</guid>
        <category>2025-03-31T00:06:16.136Z</category>
        <description>Update Although we are yet to receive a response the issue has been resolved now for nearly 6 hours. As such we will mark as resolved.
Some services are affected by a service interruption with Linode (likely related to https://status.linode.com/incidents/x14zys0wddxk). We opened a ticket 5 hours ago when it appeared as a minor issue on our monitoring however are yet to receive a response. Certain dashboard features are interrupted during this time.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; Although we are yet to receive a response the issue has been resolved now for nearly 6 hours. As such we will mark as resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some services are affected by a service interruption with Linode (likely related to &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.linode.com/incidents/x14zys0wddxk)&#34;&gt;https://status.linode.com/incidents/x14zys0wddxk)&lt;/a&gt;. We opened a ticket 5 hours ago when it appeared as a minor issue on our monitoring however are yet to receive a response. Certain dashboard features are interrupted during this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Block Storage outage</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-12-05-block-storage-outage/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 07:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-12-05-block-storage-outage/</guid>
        <category>2024-12-05T07:56:56.593Z</category>
        <description>Update Panel restored.
An outage at our cloud service provide is affecting the web panel.
No customer services are affected. Panel access will be restored when upstream resolves issue.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Panel restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outage at our cloud service provide is affecting the web panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No customer services are affected. Panel access will be restored when upstream resolves issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Paypal payments delayed</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-10-16-paypal-payments-delayed/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-10-16-paypal-payments-delayed/</guid>
        <category>2024-10-24T09:47:45.711Z</category>
        <description>Update - Still yet to receive any solution from Paypal. Only an acknowledgement of suspected fault on their end.
We are processing payments through our workaround as per normal. However there is still some element of unknown until paypal resolve the actual issue (which appears to be issues specifically with our x4b.net domain name)
As this issue does not have any known customer impact we are going to bring it to a close now.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; - Still yet to receive any solution from Paypal. Only an acknowledgement of suspected fault on their end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are processing payments through our workaround as per normal. However there is still some element of unknown until paypal resolve the actual issue (which appears to be issues specifically with our x4b.net domain name)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this issue does not have any known customer impact we are going to bring it to a close now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should you experience any delayed payments (either immeidately, or after 3 hours when the new correlation script can recover any missed payments) via paypal let us know and we will sort it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; - Still yet to receive any solution from Paypal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Transaction log check job remains in place. Having discovered a suspected workaround to the Paypal IPN system bug have implemented a workaround that appears to enable IPNs to be sent again. We will continue to run both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; - Still yet to receive any solution from Paypal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have implemented a payment check job which is able to import payments made once they are available via Paypal REST api (up to 3 hours). We understand this is inconvenient however at this time it is what we have available to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paypal&amp;rsquo;s IPN system has abruptly stopped communicating with us and we await a serious response from Paypal on this matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stripe (Credit Card) and Crypto payments are unaffected. If you need to make an urgent payment we strongly recommend using Stripe until this matter can be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigating&lt;/em&gt; - Still yet to receive any solution from Paypal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transactions are being manually processed in a priority queue. Open a support ticket if you need manual processing urgently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working on a temporary solution to reduce the delay to ~5-10 minutes while we wait on a fix from Paypal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigating&lt;/em&gt; - We are aware of delays processing paypal payments. We have contacted Paypal merchant support for a fix and are awaiting a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need a payment manually processed open a support ticket including a screenshot of your payment and we will get to it ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Scheduled Maintenance on Datastore</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-02-07-scheduled-maintenance-on-datastore/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-02-07-scheduled-maintenance-on-datastore/</guid>
        <category>2024-02-08T04:00:00.000Z</category>
        <description>We will be performing maintenance on the Datastore powering access logs, error logs, ssl logs and the filtering report tomorrow.
N﻿o significant interruption is expected however reduced performance and minor disruptions are likely.
S﻿lightly reduced performance may occur tonight as we prepare for the update.
I﻿t is possible that data collected during this time may be under representative of actual traffic and patterns.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will be performing maintenance on the Datastore powering access logs, error logs, ssl logs and the filtering report tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N﻿o significant interruption is expected however reduced performance and minor disruptions are likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S﻿lightly reduced performance may occur tonight as we prepare for the update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I﻿t is possible that data collected during this time may be under representative of actual traffic and patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Dashboard &amp; Website offline</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-01-17-dashboard-website-offline/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 09:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2024-01-17-dashboard-website-offline/</guid>
        <category>2024-01-17T11:16:02.124Z</category>
        <description>﻿Update - Vendor informs us that service is restored and is continuing to monitor (https://status.linode.com/incidents/cv0y0409nl7f)
W﻿e confirm our services website and assosiated dashboard services are back online.
﻿Update - Vendor has informed us that its an issue affecting all Block Storage in the Newyork Region and that we should expect an update soon.
Investigating - Block Storage failure affecting our database server currently has the panel offline.
W﻿e have made the vendor aware and are awaiting a fix.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;﻿Update&lt;/em&gt; - Vendor informs us that service is restored and is continuing to monitor (&lt;a href=&#34;https://status.linode.com/incidents/cv0y0409nl7f&#34;&gt;https://status.linode.com/incidents/cv0y0409nl7f&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W﻿e confirm our services website and assosiated dashboard services are back online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;﻿Update&lt;/em&gt; - Vendor has informed us that its an issue affecting all Block Storage in the Newyork Region and that we should expect an update soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Investigating&lt;/em&gt; - Block Storage failure affecting our database server currently has the panel offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W﻿e have made the vendor aware and are awaiting a fix.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Configuration update delay</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2023-05-12-configuration-update-delay/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 12:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2023-05-12-configuration-update-delay/</guid>
        <category>2023-05-12T13:21:06.152Z</category>
        <description>﻿Update service appears to have been restored for about half an hour. We havent yet got an update on our ticket. We will re-open this incident if necessary.
D﻿ue to an upstream service interruption affecting our Kubernetes cluster configuration updates are currently unavailable.
W﻿e have spoken to our upstream (Linode) and they have assured us the matter is being worked on.
W﻿hen their issue is resolved any backlogged updates will be processed.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;﻿Update&lt;/em&gt; service appears to have been restored for about half an hour. We havent yet got an update on our ticket. We will re-open this incident if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D﻿ue to an upstream service interruption affecting our Kubernetes cluster configuration updates are currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W﻿e have spoken to our upstream (Linode) and they have assured us the matter is being worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W﻿hen their issue is resolved any backlogged updates will be processed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Resolved] Client Panel &amp; Website Upgrade</title>
        <link>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2022-03-21-client-panel-website-upgrade/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://status.x4b.net/issues/2022-03-21-client-panel-website-upgrade/</guid>
        <category>2022-03-22T04:00:00.000Z</category>
        <description>Update Deployment of all queued customer configuration updates has been performed. If you are encountering any issues please do let us know.
Update Customer deployments and all customer facing services are up. If you are encountering any issues please do let us know. We will process the backlog of request for all services after a short break.
Update Most site components are are up. Customer service deployments will be available shortly.</description>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Deployment of all queued customer configuration updates has been performed. If you are encountering any issues please do let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Customer deployments and all customer facing services are up. If you are encountering any issues please do let us know. We will process the backlog of request for all services after a short break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Most site components are are up. Customer service deployments will be available shortly. Appologies that this has taken much longer than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Site is up (in dry-run mode). Changes to customer services will be deployed once we have completed full system tests. We will be taking this slowly and will update when an ETA is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; We are currently running a bit behind schedule on the first stage of the maintenance. We now hope to complete the first stage within the next 45 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Maintenance has begun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; Maintenance will begin on time in less than half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday afternoon we will be moving our web panel and database to new upgraded servers. This will consist of approximately 1 hour of panel and site outage (maintenance page) and up to 1 hour of partial ouage (dry run mode) while we complete manual tests on all components and services. During this time any customer service changes requested will be queued for execution on completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We appologies for any inconvenience this may cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will update this status announcement as appropriate with updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
